We'll now go through a few examples that you'll
现在我们来讲几个在业界做数据工作时
frequently run into when working with data in the industry,
经常会遇到的例子
and discuss whether it makes sense to use a tool like Spark.
然后讨论一下我们是否要用到 Spark 这样的工具
One of the first steps in every data problem is extraction,
数据处理的前几步就要把数据提取出来
point out just the data you need.
找到你想要的数据
Let's say you're working at a new startup named Sparkify.
假设你在一家叫 Sparkify 的创业公司工作
It's a digital music company where users can play
这家数字音乐公司提供播放歌曲服务
their favorite songs similar to Spotify or Pandora.
用户播放自己喜欢的歌曲 类似于网易云或 QQ 音乐
In order for Sparkify to grow,
为了让 Sparkify 做大做强
you need to understand how your customers use your product.
你要理解用户是如何使用你的产品的
For example, your content team needs to figure out
比如 你的内容团队想要搞清楚
which artists were played the most in Canada in the last year.
加拿大人听的最多的是谁的歌
Often, content deals are negotiated separately for each country,
大部分时候 每个国家的内容授权协议都是单独协商的
so this will help them decide which artist contracts to renew.
知道这个信息可以帮助他们决定和哪个歌手续签合同
Every time a user listen to a song in the past year,
过去一年里 每当有用户听了一首歌
the Sparkify app wrote a single record in a big log file,
Sparkify app 都会写记录到一个大的日志文件里
which you downloaded on your laptop overnight.
夜里把日志下载到电脑里
Each record, contains a large number of fields,
每个记录都包括一堆字段
the song, the artists, timestamps,
比如 歌名 歌手 时间戳
and user information like name,
以及 用户信息 如 名字
geographic location, browser information,
地区 浏览器信息等
and much, much more.
不一而足
The first step is to pull out the subset of
第一步就是把你需要的那部分信息
data that you care about from the raw data logs.
从原始的日志文件中提取出来
In this case, we only need the artist for Canadian users,
这个例子中 我们只需要知道加拿大用户听过的歌手信息
so our processing is pretty simple.
所以我们的处理也很简单
You filter out all the non Canadian users,
你把非加拿大用户剔除
and extract the artist field.
然后把歌手相关字段提取出来
Since Sparkify is still small,
因为 Sparkily 用户不多
and you only have a few thousand users,
只有几千个
this data is modest in size.
数据量也不大
The last year of data is only four gigs,
去年一年的数据只有4 G
so it easily fit into the eight gigabytes of memory on your laptop.
一下把所有数据加载到 8 G 的内存里也没问题
This means that you can load all the data sequentially in your memory,
于是你可以把所有的数据按顺序加载到内存里
and you can write a simple Python program to have
你可以写个简单的 Python 程序让
your CPU filter and extract the artists.
CPU 把歌手信息过滤提取出来
Since you're at an adventurous startup,
因为你在的初创公司很有冒险精神
willing to try anything,
愿意尝试所有事情
you spend a while thinking if there's an easier way to process the data.
于是你想了想 有没有其他更便捷的方式处理这部分数据
One possible idea is to split the data.
一个方式就是把数据拆分开
Perhaps, emailing a month of data to 12 of your co-workers laptops.
或许可以把每个月的数据发到不同同事们的电脑里
They could each run your Python program,
让他们跑你的 Python 程序
and then email you back the results when they're done.
然后把结果发还给你
But this one would be worth it.
但是这并不值得
Emailing the data across the network is the slowest part of this process.
通过网络来发数据是整个过程中最慢的
Also, what if one of your co-workers is using Python 2 but your program uses Python 3,
而且如果有个同事用的是 Python 2 但是你的程序是用 Python 3 写的呢
now your code won't work.
这样你的代码就会报错了
Or what if another co-worker was busy,
或者另外一个同事太忙了
and took an extra 20 minutes to start the program?
多等了 20 分钟才开始跑程序
Even if you have 11 months of data,
即使你有了 11 个月的数据
you don't know the most popular artist until you have all the results back.
你也只能等第 12 个月的数据结果才能知道谁是最受欢迎的歌手
These are some of the problems you run into when you have distributed systems like Spark.
当你用 Spark 这样的分布式系统时就会遇到上面的问题了
In this case, it's easier to stick to go Python.
这个例子里我们直接用 Python 就行了
So, according to our definition,
所以根据我们的定义
you don't have big data.
你的数据不能叫做大数据